Guide to the Yale Review Records: 1911-1949
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Yale Review records
1911-1949
YCAL MSS 145
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
5.86
(14 boxes)
The papers consist of business correspondence, sometimes accompanied by submissions and proofs, between the editors of the Yale Review and the writers whose works appeared in the journal. Authors represented include John Jay Chapman, Walter De la Mare, Robert Frost, William Inge, Walter Lippmann, William Lyon Phelps, Edward Arlington Robinson, Sara Teasdale, and Louis Untermeyer.
Yale Review
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Primarily gift of the Yale Review office, 1949-1950. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Associated Materials
Yale Review Records: 1956-1979, Uncat.ZA MS.383
Wilbur Lucius Cross Papers, Department of Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University.
Scope and Contents
The Yale Review Records: 1911-1949 consist primarily of business correspondence between the first two editors of The Yale Review, Wilbur L. Cross and Helen MacAfee, and writers whose works appeared in the periodical during their tenures. The collection has been organized into one series, Correspondence, arranged alphabetically by author; "letter general" files, which as a rule contain correspondents represented by relatively few items, precede the individual files under each letter. The records span the years 1911-1959, with the bulk of the material dating from between 1925 and 1940.
Series I, Correspondence, is housed in boxes 1-13 and contains letters from contributors and potential contributors to the magazine, accompanied by retained carbons of letters by Cross and MacAfee. Occasional third party correspondence from literary agents or translators with the editors has been filed with the writer's correspondence. Typical subjects include: solicitations and offers of articles on specific topics, discussion of the magazine's low payment rates, suggestions for editorial changes, and comment on the magazine's quality and contents. Some letters also contain personal and family news, literary opinions, and sometimes lengthy discussions of current events and economic concerns such as a proposed nationalization of the power industry in the United States or the effect of offyear elections on foreign relations and monetary policy.
Several files also contain manuscripts and proofs of submissions, including poems by Stephen Vincent Benét, Walter De La Mare, Robert Frost, John Masefield, Edwin Arlington Robinson, and Allen Tate; articles by Clemence Dane, E.M. Forster, Stephen Grahame, Harold Laski, Sean O'Faolain, George Santayana, and H. G. Wells; and book reviews by Charles Morgan, Ida B. Tarbell and Rebecca West. In many cases, the manuscripts and proofs are principal subjects of the correspondence, as the authors and editors discuss the works and the publication process; in others, these items appear to be unconnected to the surviving correspondence, or are entirely unaccompanied by letters. These materials have been identified in folder notes.
Yale Review; American literature -- Periodicals; American literature -- 20th Century; Authors and publishers -- United States; English literature -- 20th Century; Periodicals -- Publishing -- United States; Social sciences -- Periodicals; Authors; Editors; Adams, James Truslow, 1878-1949; Chapman, John Jay, 1862-1933; Cross, Wilbur L. (Wilbur Lucius), 1862-1948; De la Mare, Walter, 1873-1956; Fletcher, John Gould, 1886-1950; Frost, Robert, 1874-1963; Inge, William Ralph, 1860-1954; Jusserand, J. J. (Jean Jules), 1855-1932; Lippmann, Walter, 1889-1974; MacAfee, Helen; Phelps, William Lyon, 1865-1943; Repplier, Agnes, 1855-1950; Teasdale, Sara, 1884-1933; Untermeyer, Louis, 1885-1977; Woolf, Virginia, 1882-1941
- Correspondence, 1907-1953; Series I; 5.46; (13 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Correspondence, is alphabetically arranged by author. "Letter general" files precede files of individual authors within each letter.
  - "A" general, 1912-1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Adams, T.S.
    Ainslie, Douglas
    Alden, H.M.
    Altrocchi, J.C.
    Anthony, Katharine
  - Aberdeen, Lady, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Acheson, Dean, 1937-1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Adamic, Louis, 1933-1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Adams, Brooks, 1910-1921 (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
    With typescript carbon and typescript carbon, corrected, of Bunker Hill Association Address
  - Adams, Charles F., 1914 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Adams, Franklin P., 1942 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Adams, G. B., 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Adams, Henry, 1913-1915 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Adams, James Truslow, 1929-1944 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
  - Addams, Jane, 1911-1920 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Aiken, Conrad, 1919-1934 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Aldington, Richard, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Allen, Frederick Lewis, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Allen, Henry E., 1939 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Allen, Hervey, 1928-1929 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Anderson, Sherwood, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Andrew, A. Piatt, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Andrews, C. F., 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Anesaki, Masaharu, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Angell, James Rowland, 1924-1941 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Angell, Norman, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Ascoli, Max, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Atherton, Gertrude, 1912-1914 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Austin, Mary, 1930-1931 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - "Ba-Bl" general, 1921-1945 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Bacon, Thomas R.
    Ballou, Adin
    Barker, Virgil
    Barton, Joan
    Bechtel, Edwin, Mrs.
    Benchley, Robert
    Bidwell, Geney W.
    Bizzell, W.B.
    Bloomfield, Leonard
    Blunt, Katharine
  - "Bo-Br" general, 1916-1946 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Bodenheim, Maxwell
    Bolte, Charles G.
    Bonbright, James C.
    Bonn, Moritz J.
    Borden, Robert L.
    Bosanquet, Theodore
    Bradley, William A.
    Bragg, W.L.
    Brandt & Brandt
    Brent, Charles H., Bishop
    Brewer, Edward Vere
    Bridgman, P.W.
    Bronson, F.W.
    Brookhouser, Frank
    Brown, Ivor
  - "Bu-By" general, 1913-1937 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Buell, R.L.
    Bull, Ludlow S.
    Burke, Thomas
    Burlingham, Charles C.
    Bury, J.B.
    Bushnell, Sam C.
    Butler, Ellen Parker
    Butler, Nicholas Murray
    Butler, Pierce
    Byrd, Harry F
  - Babbit, Irving, 1915-1924 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Bacon, Leonard, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Baker, George P., 1918-1930 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Baker, Newton D., 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Baldwin, Simeon E., 1911-1919 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Barrie, James M., Sir, 1920-1922 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Baruch, Bernard M., 1940-1950 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Bates, Katharine Lee, 1917-1926 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Beard, Charles A., 1927-1943 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Beatty, Albert R., 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Becker, Carl, 1937-1945 (Box 1, Folder 42-44)
  - Beer, George Louis, 1917-1918 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Beers, Henry A., 1911-1925 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Belloc, Hilaire, 1914-1932 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1926-1941 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    Includes typescript carbon, signed, of a version of "American Names"
  - Benét, William Rose, 1907-1927 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Bennett, Arnold, 1917-1919 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Bennett, Charles A., 1920-1930 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Bergson, Henri, 1913-1926 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Beveridge, Albert J., 1920-1921 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Bianchi, Martha Dickinson, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Blunden, Edmund, 1921-1922 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    With holographs, signed, of five poems
  - Borglum, Gutzon, 1913-1921 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Bose, Jagadis Chandre, 1926-1927 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Bourne, Randolph, 1917-1919 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    With ALS from Agnes de Lima to Yale Review, 1919
  - Boyle, Kay, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Bradford, Gamaliel, 1912-1925 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Brailsford, H. N., 1927-1928 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    With holograph and typescript, corrected, of "Candide Returns to Earth"
  - Branch, Anna Hempstead, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Bridges, Robert, 1920-1923 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Brooke, Tucker, 1925-1944 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck, 1922-1941 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Brown, E.K., 1943-1946 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Brown, John Mason, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Brownell, William Cary, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Bryce, James Bryce, Viscount, 1914-1921 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Buck, Pearl S., 1936-1941 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Burroughs, John, 1913-1920 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Bynner, Witter, 1912-1927 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    With typescript signed, heavily corrected, of "Surety"
  - "Ca-Col" general, 1913-1945 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    Cabot, Philip
    Callaghan, Morley
    Cane, Melville
    Cardozo, Benjamin N.
    Carman, Bliss
    Carmer, Carl
    Carnegie, H.
    Cary, Robert H.
    Cason, Clarence E.
    Catt, Carrie Chapman, Mrs.
    Cesrie, C.
    Channings, Edmund
    Chamberlin, Ernest V.
    Chapman, H.H.
    Childs, Marquis W.
    Clapper, Raymond
    Clark, Charles E.
    Clark, J.M.
    Clark, Margaret
    Clayton, E.
    Cohen, M.
    Colder, Frank
    Cole, Allan B.
  - "Con-Cu" general, 1912-1945 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    Conkling, F.H.
    Conover, Milton
    Cooper, Louise Field
    Copland, Howard
    Coppard, A.E.
    Corbett, P.E.
    Corle, Edwin
    Cournos, John
    Covell, Henry H., Dr.
    Cowles, John
    Cox, Kenyon
    Craig, Edward Gordon
    Cram, Ralph Adams
    Cranston, Ruth
    Cross, John Walter
    Culbertson, William S.
    Cunningham, Larabie
    Curle, Richard
    Curtis Brown, Ltd.
  - Cabell, James Branch, 1920-1922 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Caldwell, Erskine, 1933-1934 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Cammaerts, Emile, 1921-1922 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Campbell, William March, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Cather, Willa, 1921-1933 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Cecil, Robert Cecil, Viscount, 1922-1935 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Chamberlin, William Henry, 1929-1943 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Chang, Hsin-Hai, 1921-1942 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Chapman, John Jay, 1917-1931 (Box 2, Folder 83-84)
  - Chase, Mary Ellen, 1931-1947 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Churchill, Winston S., 1916-1929 (Box 2, Folder 86-87)
  - Ciardi, John, 1940-1946 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Clark, Grenville, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Clark, Walter van Tilburg, 1941-1944 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Colum, Mary M., 1932-1935 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Colum, Padraic, 1921-1941 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Compton, Arthur H., 1930-1935 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Conant, James B., 1935-1946 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Cooper, James Fenimore, Jr., 1914-1922 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Copland, Douglas Berry, 1936-1937 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Corbett, H.W., 1928-1935 (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Cortissoz, Royal, 1923-1932 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Croce, Benedetto, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Cromer, Lord, 1916-1917 (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Crothers, Samuel M., 1912-1920 (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Cushing, Harvey, 1915-1928 (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - "Da-Di" general, 1911-1946 (Box 3, Folder 103)
    Damboehler, Helem, Mrs.
    Daniels, Earl
    Daniels, Jonathan
    Davies, W.H.
    Davignon, Henri
    Davis, E.H.
    Davison, Frank Dalby
    Day, Clive
    Day, L.T., Mrs.
    Day, George P.
    Dealey, Eward M.
    Dean, Vera Micheles
    De Kiewiet, C.W.
    Deland, Margarite
    Dell, Robert
    De Mille, William C.
    Deutsch, Babette
    Dewey, John
    Dickinson, John
    Dillon, E.J.
    Dimnet, Ernest
  - "Do-Du" general, 1918-1936 (Box 3, Folder 104)
    Dobree, Bonamy
    Dodd, William E.
    Dominian, N.
    Donnay, M. Maurice
    Douglas, Norman
    Duggan, Stephen P.
    Dukes, Ashley
  - Day, Clarence S., 1915-1924 (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Dane, Clemence, 1925-1933 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    With typsecript and galley proof, corrected, of "The Loved Elizabeth"
  - Davis, Elmer, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - De la Mare, Walter, 1917-1944 (Box 3, Folder 108-110)
    With holograph of "Fare-well" and "Nightfall;" galley proofs, corrected, of "Lipsett, Lipsett, and Vane;" typescript and galley proofs, corrected, of "The Orgy"
  - De Wit, Augusta, 1918-1920 (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - Dodd, Lee Wilson, 1911-1930 (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - Dodds, Harold W., 1935-1942 (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - Douglas, William O., 1934-1939 (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - Drinkwater, John, 1919-1959 (Box 3, Folder 115-116)
    With typescript corrected, signed, of "Absence" and "Hereafter"
  - Dwight, Harry G., 1916-1934 (Box 3, Folder 117)
  - "E" general, 1911-1946 (Box 4, Folder 118)
    Earle, Edward Meade
    Eastman, Max
    Eaton, Theodore H., Jr.
    Eaton, Walter P.
    Ebright, Frederick
    Eddington, A.J.
    Edib, Halidi
    Edwards, Cecil
    Edwards, Clara Cary
    Elliott, W.Y.
    Elton, Oliver
    Erskine, R.
  - Einstein, Albert, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 119)
    Third-party correspondence concerning a possible Einstein article
  - Eiselen, Malcolm R., 1936 (Box 4, Folder 120)
  - Eliot, Charles W., 1921-1923 (Box 4, Folder 121)
  - Eliot, T.S., 1936 (Box 4, Folder 122)
  - Ellis, Havelock, 1911-1939 (Box 4, Folder 123)
  - Erskine, John, 1911-1945 (Box 4, Folder 124)
  - Ervine, St. John, 1920-1937 (Box 4, Folder 125)
  - "F" general, 1915-1946 (Box 4, Folder 126)
    Fadiman, Clifton
    Farbman, M.S.
    Farnam, Henry W.
    Farrelly, Theodore S.
    Feiler, Arthur
    Ferril, Thomas H.
    Fifield, William
    Fineman, Irving
    Fisher, H.A.L.
    Flanner, Janet
    Fleming, Berry
    Floyd, Olive Beatrice
    Flynn, John T.
    Fontaine, Robert
    Ford, Worthington C.
    Forster, Max
    Franck, Harry A.
    Frankenberg, Lloyd
    Friedrich, Carl J.
    Frost, Frances
  - Fay, Minnie Chandler, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 127)
  - Fay, Sidney B., 1924-1942 (Box 4, Folder 128)
  - Ferber, Edna, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 129)
  - Feuillerat, Albert, 1921-1931 (Box 4, Folder 130)
  - Finley, John H., 1917-1927 (Box 4, Folder 131)
  - Fischer, Louis, 1929-1930 (Box 4, Folder 132)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, 1943-1945 (Box 4, Folder 133)
  - Flanner, Hildegarde, 1922-1940 (Box 4, Folder 134)
  - Fletcher, John Gould, 1919-1928 (Box 4, Folder 135-137)
  - Ford, Ford Madox, 1920-1929 (Box 4, Folder 138)
    With typescripts carbon, corrected, of "The Miracle" and "Working with Conrad"
  - Forster, E.M., 1925-1926 (Box 4, Folder 139)
    With setting typescript, corrected, of "The Art of Virginia Woolf"
  - Frankfurter, Felix, 1916-1935 (Box 4, Folder 140)
  - Freeman, Mary E. Wilkins, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 141)
  - Frost, Robert, 1915-1945 (Box 4, Folder 142-145)
    With holographs, signed, of "Geode,"
    "Master Speed," "The Minor Bird,"
    "Voice-Ways," "The Rose Family,"
    "The White-Tailed Hornet," "The
    Bearer of Evil Tidings," "The
    Common Fate," and "Departmental;"
    typescripts, corrected and signed,
    of "Geode" and "Maple;" typescripts,
    signed of "After-Flakes," "I Could
    Give All to Time," "A Missive
    Missile," "Nocturnes," "Moon
    Compasses," "Neither Out Far Nor In
    Deep," "Snow Dust," "The Onset,"
    "A Star in a Stone-boat," and
    "Misgiving;" and galley proofs,
    corrected and signed, of "Nocturnes,"
    "A Group of Poems," and "Neither Out
    Far Nor In Deep"
  - "Ga-Gi" general, 1913-1946 (Box 4, Folder 146)
    Gabrilowitsch, O.
    Galantière, Lewis
    Gannett, Lewis
    Ganoe, William A.
    Gay, H. Nelson
    Geismar, Maxwell
    Gibbons, James, Cardinal
    Gibbs, Philip
    Gill, Richard C.
  - "Gl-Gra" general, 1922-1946 (Box 4, Folder 147)
    Gleason, Lafayette B.
    Goddard, Harold C.
    Gordon, Caroline
    Gowen, Emmett
    Graham, Kenneth
    Grant-Watson, E.L.
    Gray, George W.
    Gray, Peter
  - "Gre-Gw" general, 1918-1944 (Box 4, Folder 148)
    Green, Anne
    Greene, Francis V.
    Greene, P.F., Mrs.
    Greenfield, Kent Roberts
    Gregg, Alan
    Grinnell, George B.
    Grogan, Elmira
    Guedalla, Philip
    Gulick, Sidney Lewis, Jr.
    Gummere, Francis B.
    Gwynn, Stephen
  - Gale, Zona, 1921-1936 (Box 5, Folder 149-150)
    With typescript carbon, signed, of "Duplication"
  - Galsworthy, John, 1913-1930 (Box 5, Folder 151-152)
    With typescript, corrected, signed, and galley proof, corrected, signed, of "Castles in Spain"
  - Gardiner, William Howard, 1922-1925 (Box 5, Folder 153)
  - Garland, Hamlin, 1913-1922 (Box 5, Folder 154)
  - Garvin, J.L., 1926-1928 (Box 5, Folder 155)
  - Gerould, Katharine Fullerton, 1917-1930 (Box 5, Folder 156)
  - Gibson, Wilfred Wilson, 1915-1920 (Box 5, Folder 157)
  - Gide, André, 1931-1939 (Box 5, Folder 158)
    Galley proof, corrected, of "Henry James," with third-party correspondence
  - Gifford, Fannie Stearns (Davis), 1912-1913 (Box 5, Folder 159)
  - Gilbreath, Olive, 1917-1919 (Box 5, Folder 160)
  - Gilman, Lawrence, 1919-1920 (Box 5, Folder 161)
  - Girsa, Vaclar, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 162)
  - Glasgow, Ellen, 1926-1944 (Box 5, Folder 163)
  - Golding, Louis, 1924-1934 (Box 5, Folder 164)
    With "Louis Golding, A Biographical Sketch," printed
  - Goodyear, A.C., 1925-1926 (Box 5, Folder 165)
  - Grahame, Stephen, 1916-1917 (Box 5, Folder 166)
    With holograph, signed, of "America and the Near East"
  - Grant, Robert, 1916-1925 (Box 5, Folder 167)
  - Granville-Barker, H., 1926-1931 (Box 5, Folder 168)
  - Greenfield, Kent Roberts, 1940-1947 (Box 5, Folder 169)
  - Gregory, Horace, 1938-1943 (Box 5, Folder 170)
  - Grelling, Richard, 1921-1926 (Box 5, Folder 171)
  - Guérard, Albert, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 172)
  - "Ha" general, 1924-1945 (Box 5, Folder 173)
    Hackett, Francis
    Haig, Robert M.
    Hailey, Foster
    Halle, Louis
    Halper, Albert
    Hamilton, Walton H.
    Hampden, Walter
    Hanc, Josef
    Hand, Learned, Judge
    Handy, Willowdean C., Mrs.
    Hardwick, Elizabeth
    Harper, George McLean
    Harris, Nurray
    Harrison, Henry S.
    Hart, Albert Bushnell
    Hart, Lawrence
    Havill, Edward
  - "He" general, 1915-1946 (Box 5, Folder 174)
    Head, Henry
    Hélion, Jean
    Henderson, Archibald
    Henderson, Arthur
    Henderson, W.J.
    Henrich, Edith
    Herring, Hubert
    Herskovits, Melville J.
    Heth, Edward H.
  - "Hi-Ho" general, 1917-1947 (Box 5, Folder 175)
    Hickey, Joseph J.
    Hill, David J.
    Hindus, M.G.
    Hirst, Francis W.
    Hocking, William E.
    Hogan, John V.L.
    Holland, Robert E., Sir
    Hood, Thomas L.
    Horan, Robert
    Hotson, Leslie
    House, Edward M.
    Howard, Esme, J.
    Howard, Joseph Kinsey
    Howe, Quincy
    Howland, Charles P.
  - "Hu" general, 1912-1944 (Box 5, Folder 176)
    Hughes, Helen Sard
    Hughes, Rupert
    Hughes, Richard
    Hume, Cyril
    Hume, Robert
    Humphries, Rolfe
    Hurst, Julius H., Dr.
    Hutchinson, F. Evelyn
  - Hadley, Arthur T., 1914-1929 (Box 5, Folder 177)
    With typescript carbon, corrected, of "The Basis of Modern Democracy"
  - Hale, Richard W., 1931-1932 (Box 5, Folder 178)
  - Haldane, Richard, 1916-1919 (Box 5, Folder 179)
  - Hanotaux, Gabriel, 1926-1927 (Box 5, Folder 180)
    With typescripts carbon, corrected, of "La situation actuelle de la France" and an English version.
  - Hansen, Alvin, 1936-1941 (Box 5, Folder 181)
  - Hardy, Thomas, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 182)
  - Hazlitt, Henry, 1942-1944 (Box 6, Folder 183)
  - Hergesheimer, Joseph, 1920-1921 (Box 6, Folder 184)
  - Herrick, Robert, 1922-1924 (Box 6, Folder 185)
  - Hinkson, Pamela, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 186)
  - Holloway, R. Emory, 1914-1915 (Box 6, Folder 187)
  - Holmes, John, 1933-1944 (Box 6, Folder 188)
  - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1915-1920 (Box 6, Folder 189)
  - Holst, Gustav, 1922-1929 (Box 6, Folder 190)
  - Hooker, Brian, 1911-1917 (Box 6, Folder 191)
  - Hooker, Richard, 1927-1945 (Box 6, Folder 192)
  - Horgan, Paul, 1928-1944 (Box 6, Folder 193)
  - Housman, A.E., 1917-1927 (Box 6, Folder 194)
  - Housman, Laurence, 1916-1940 (Box 6, Folder 195)
  - Howe, M.A. de Wolfe, 1918-1942 (Box 6, Folder 196)
  - Hoyt, Edith, 1918-1920 (Box 6, Folder 197)
  - Hughes, Charles Evans, 1916-1929 (Box 6, Folder 198)
  - Hutchins, Robert M., 1927-1931 (Box 6, Folder 199)
  - Huxley, Julian S., 1925-1941 (Box 6, Folder 200)
  - Huxley, Leonard, 1922-1923 (Box 6, Folder 201)
  - Hyde, Charles Cheney, 1915-1933 (Box 6, Folder 202)
  - Inge, William Ralph, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 203-204)
    With holographs of "The Social Message of the Church," "Church and State in England," and "Religion in England after the War"
  - Ivins, William M., 1922 (Box 6, Folder 205)
  - "J" general, 1921-1947 (Box 6, Folder 206)
    Jackson, Shirley
    James, Edward
    Jastrow, Joseph
    Jaszi, Oscar
    Johnson, Elizabeth Winthrop
    Johnson, Geoffrey
    Johnson, Hiram W.
    Johnson, O.
    Johnston, Mary
    Jones, Eleanor Clement
    Jones, Reginald, Mrs.
    Jordan, Virgil
  - Jacks, L.P., 1913-1936 (Box 6, Folder 207)
  - James, Henry (1843-1916), 1915 (Box 6, Folder 208)
  - James, Henry (1879-1947), 1923-1935 (Box 6, Folder 209)
  - Jameson, Storm, 1921 (Box 6, Folder 210)
  - Johnson, Alvin, 1932-1948 (Box 6, Folder 211)
  - Johnson, Robert Underwood, 1915-1918 (Box 6, Folder 212)
  - Johnston, Harry H., Sir, 1920-1926 (Box 6, Folder 213)
  - Jones, Howard Mumford, 1924-1933 (Box 6, Folder 214)
  - Jones, Robert Edmond, 1927-1937 (Box 6, Folder 215)
  - Jusserand, J.J., 1921-1926 (Box 6, Folder 216-217)
  - "Ka-Ke" general, 1917-1946 (Box 6, Folder 218)
    Kaempffert, Waldemar
    Karpovich, Michael
    Kawakami, K.
    Kayden, Eugene M.
    Kaye-Smith, Sheila
    Keen, W.W.,
    Kellogg, Vernon
    Kelly, Florence Finch
    Kelly, Howard A.
    Kennan, George
    Kent, Ralph
    Kent, Sherman
  - "Ki-Kw" general, 1925-1943 (Box 6, Folder 219)
    Kimball, Fiske
    King, Mary
    Kinney, Troy
    Kirkwood, J.G.
    Knollenberg, Bernhard
    Köhler, Wolfgang
    Koteliansky, S.S.
    Koudrey, Vladimir
    Krutch, Joseph W.
    Kwei, C.T., Mrs.
  - Keller, Albert G., 1911-1944 (Box 7, Folder 220)
  - Kent, William, 1919-1925 (Box 7, Folder 221)
  - Keynes, John Maynard, 1931-1933 (Box 7, Folder 222)
  - Keyserling, Hermann, 1926-1927 (Box 7, Folder 223)
  - King, Grace, 1921-1929 (Box 7, Folder 224)
  - Kipling, Rudyard, 1914 (Box 7, Folder 225)
  - Komroff, Manuel, 1929-1930 (Box 7, Folder 226)
  - "La-Leg" general, 1911-1942 (Box 7, Folder 227)
    La Farge, Bancel, Mrs.
    Landis, James M.
    Lanson, M. Gustav
    Latourette, K.S.
    Lattimore, Owen
    Lavarenne, Maurice M.
    Lawrence, William, Rev.
    Leawik, Stephen
    LeDoux, Louis V.
    Legouis, Emile
  - "Les-Li" general, 1913-1947 (Box 7, Folder 228)
    Leslie, Shane
    Le Sueur, Meridel
    Levinson, Ronald B.
    Lewis, Evans
    Lewis, Edward R.
    Lewisohn, Ludwig
    Lindbergh, Anne M.
    Linebarger, Paul M.A.
    Linn, Bettina
    Litchfield, Cora, Mrs.
    Litchfield, Norman, Mrs.
    Littell, Philip
  - "Lo-Ly" general, 1912-1941 (Box 7, Folder 229)
    Lockwood, William W.
    Loeb, Jacques
    Lothian, Marquess of
    Lothrop, Margaret M.
    Low, Maurice
    Lowe, Pardee
    Lowell, A. Lawrence
    Lubbock, Percy
    Lucas, Audrey, Mrs.
    Lusk, Graham
    Lybyer, Albert H.
    Lyman, Hart
    Lynd, Robert
  - Ladd, George Trumbull, 1917-1919 (Box 7, Folder 230)
  - Lamont, Thomas W., 1922-1932 (Box 7, Folder 231)
  - Langner, Lawrence, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 232)
  - Langer, William L., 1938-1940 (Box 7, Folder 233)
  - Laski, Harold J., 1918-1938 (Box 7, Folder 234)
    With holograph, corrected, of "The Changing Civil Service"
  - Lawrence, D.H., 1917 (Box 7, Folder 235)
  - Leffingwell, R.C., 1922-1947 (Box 7, Folder 236)
  - Lerner, Max, 1926-1934 (Box 7, Folder 237)
  - Letts, W.M., 1916-1933 (Box 7, Folder 238)
  - Lewis, Wilmarth S., 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 239)
  - Liddell, Hart, B.H., 1930-1945 (Box 7, Folder 240)
  - Lindsay, Vachel, 1913-1916 (Box 7, Folder 241)
  - Lippmann, Walter, 1915-1933 (Box 7, Folder 242-243)
  - Littell, Robert, 1928-1942 (Box 7, Folder 244)